metabolicdesign.com 2018-02-12

# Privacy – Metabolic Design

## Privacy Policy

Metabolic Design LLC. is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the Metabolic Design LLC. website and governs data collection and usage. By using the Metabolic Design LLC. website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

### Collection of your Personal Information

Metabolic Design LLC. collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. Metabolic Design LLC. also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by Metabolic Design LLC. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used by Metabolic Design LLC. for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Metabolic Design LLC. website.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through Metabolic Design LLC. public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: Metabolic Design LLC. does not read any of your private online communications.

Metabolic Design LLC. encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from Metabolic Design LLC. so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. Metabolic Design LLC. is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside the Metabolic Design LLC. and Metabolic Design LLC. family of websites.

### Use of your Personal Information

Metabolic Design LLC. collects and uses your personal information to operate the Metabolic Design LLC. website and deliver the services you have requested. Metabolic Design LLC. also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Metabolic Design LLC. and its affiliates. Metabolic Design LLC. may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

Metabolic Design LLC. does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. Metabolic Design LLC. may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, Metabolic Design LLC. may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Metabolic Design LLC., and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Metabolic Design LLC. does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

Metabolic Design LLC. keeps track of the websites and pages our customers visit within Metabolic Design LLC., in order to determine what Metabolic Design LLC. services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within Metabolic Design LLC. to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

Metabolic Design LLC. websites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) Conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Metabolic Design LLC. or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Metabolic Design LLC.; and (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Metabolic Design LLC., or the public.

### Use of Cookies

The Metabolic Design LLC. website uses “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web-page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Metabolic Design LLC. pages, or register with Metabolic Design LLC. site or services, a cookie helps Metabolic Design LLC. to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same Metabolic Design LLC. website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the Metabolic Design LLC. features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Metabolic Design LLC. services or websites you visit.

### Security of your Personal Information

Metabolic Design LLC. secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Metabolic Design LLC. secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit-card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

### Changes to this Statement

Metabolic Design LLC. will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. Metabolic Design LLC. encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Metabolic Design LLC. is protecting your information.

### Contact Information

Metabolic Design LLC. welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that Metabolic Design LLC. has not adhered to this Statement, please contact Metabolic Design LLC. at support@metabolicdesign.com. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
